# Son Nguyen

### Project Manager

Phone774-987-4009

Linkedinlinkedin.com/johnutw

E-Mailj.smith@cvmaker.pro

Twitter@johnsmithutw



#### **SUMMARY**



IT Professional with over 10 years of experience specializing in IT department management for international logistics companies. I can implement effective IT strategies at local and global levels. My greatest strength is business awareness, which enables me to permanently streamline infrastructure and applications.



#### **EXPERIENCE**

2006-12 -

**Senior Project Manager** 

present

Seton Hospital, ME

- Oversaw all major hospital IT projects for 10+ years, focus on cost reduction.
- Responsible for creating, improving, and developing IT project strategies.
- Implemented the highly successful Lean Training and Six Sigma projects for all employees.
- I reduced the costs of IT infrastructure maintenance by 5% in 2015 by successfully rebuilding the infrastructure.
- 2004-09 -

**Junior Project Manager** 

2006-12

Seton Hospital, ME

- Streamlined IT logistics and administration operation cutting costs by 25%.
- Diagnosed problems with hardware and operating systems and implemented solutions to increase efficiency.
- Maintained the user database of over 30000 patients, implemented new solutions inside the dashboard.
- Managed project for lean training for all IT Support Officers.



## **EDUCATION**

1996-09 -

**Master of Computer Science, University of Maryland** 

2001-05

- Graduated Summa Cum Laude.
- Member of Student Association of Project Management
- Managed a student project to develop a weekly IT News podcast.



#### **SKILLS**

- Business Process Improvement- history of successful innovations leading to cost savings.
- **Vendor Management** proven track record of managing vendors in projects with budgets of over \$1'000'000.
- Project Scheduling- over 90% of projects led were finished in due time.
- Sales Analysis- background in IT Sales with deep understanding of negotiating contracts.



## **CERTIFICATIONS**

**2015-05** PMP - Project Management Institute

2014-04 PRINCE2® Foundation